Survival is no game
Tekken is a crime, drama, action film directed by Dwight H. Little.
In the year of 2039, after World Wars destroy much of the civilization as we know it, territories are no
longer run by governments, but by corporations; the mightiest of which is the Mishima Zaibatsu.
In order to placate the seething masses of this dystopia, Mishima sponsors Tekken, a
tournament in which fighters battle until only one is left standing.
Jin Kazama, played by Jonathan Patrick Foo.
Christie Monteiro, played by Kelly Overton.
Heihachi Mishima, played by Cary-Hiroyuki Tagawa.
Kazuya, played by Ian Anthony Dale.
Steve Fox, played by Luke Goss.
Eddy Gordo, played by Lateef Crowder.
Tekken is a 2009 American science fiction martial arts film loosely based on the video game
series of the same name developed and published by Namco / Bandai Games, Inc.
It was directed by Dwight Little from a screenplay by Alan B.
The film stars Jon Foo, Kelly Overton, Cary-Hiroyuki Tagawa, Ian Anthony Dale,
Cung Le, Darrin Dewitt Henson, Candice Hillebrand, and Luke Goss.
The plot follows Jin Kazama in his attempts to enter the Iron Fist Tournament in order to avenge the loss of his
mother, Jun Kazama, by confronting the forces of the city that are also holding the competition.
The film was originally announced by publisher Namco / Bandai in
2002, but did not start development until 2007.
Experienced in sports movies, Little decided to make Tekken focused on realism, resulting in the removal
of supernatural elements from the video game series as well as comic relief characters.
This also led to the inclusion of martial artists as the main
cast to produce well-choreographed battles.
Tekken premiered at the American Film Market on November 5, 2009, and was released
direct-to-video in the United States on July 19, 2011, by Anchor Bay Entertainment.
The film bombed at the box office with a gross of $1.6 million worldwide.
Critical reception was unfavorable, with the film generally praised for its fighting scenes, but
criticized for its unfaithful narrative and poor acting within the main cast.
The criticism also came from the video game series'
executive director Katsuhiro Harada.
Nevertheless, Tekken spawned the 2014 prequel Tekken 2: Kazuya's Revenge.
The film explores themes of martial arts, dystopia, based on
video game, martial arts tournament, 2030s.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking and intense.